Sigmund Freud Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Oversize, 1859-1985 (Box OV 1-OV 20)
  - Writings* (Container 50A) (Box OV 2, Reel 1)
    - Undated (Box OV 14, Reel 6)
      - “My Subconscious Jewishness,” clipping from the Current Jewish Record
      - [Notes and doodles], negative and positive photocopies of holograph manuscripts
      - [Notes for a contribution to the Internationale Zeitschrift für Psychoanalyse, II, 1914, re: homosexuality and hormones (?)], holograph manuscript with photocopy
      - [Notes on dreams: absurdity, déjà vu, and principles], holograph manuscripts with photocopies
      - [Résumé], holograph manuscript
      - [Skizze], holograph manuscript with photocopy of typewritten transcript
      - [Unidentified fragments], holograph manuscript and typed transcripts
      - [Unidentified hand and typewritten manuscripts]
      - [Unidentified jottings] [“nachlass”], holograph manuscripts
      - [Unidentified notes], holograph and photocopied manuscripts
        - Folder 1
        - Folder 2
        - Folder 3“Verlorene Tendenzen in der Kunst,” photocopy of holograph manuscript
      - “Verschiedene Stile der indirekten Darstellung,” holograph manuscript with photocopy
      - “Vortrag,” photocopy of holograph manuscript
      - Writing not in Freud's hand concerning the “Kakao” analogy, photocopy of holograph manuscript
  - Supplemental File (Box OV 15)
    - Subject File
      - Augenfeld, Felix
        - Floor plan of Freud's London, England, study and sketch of display cabinets, 1973, undated (Container 51)
      - Centenary of Freud's birth
        - Exhibit material
          - Items arranged according to a numeric scheme, 1897-1940, undated (Container 52)
          - Miscellany, 1931, 1956-1959 (Container 52)
          - Photographs and drawings, 1911 (Container 52)
          - Printed matter, 1921, undated (Container 52)
      - Freud family history (Container 58)
        - Family trees by
          - Freud, Jechiel, 1914
          - Marcer, Roberto C., undated (Box OV 16)
      - “The Growth of the Psycho-Analytic Movement,” map and chart, undated (Container 60) (Box OV 17)
      - Hoffman, Paul, program and publicity for his dramatic readings of Freud's writings, 1976 (Container 60) (Box OV 18)
    - Miscellany
      - Pictorial printed matter including calendars, greeting card, postcards, and prints, 1960, 1965, undated (Container 136)
  - Additions (Box OV 19)
    - 2010 addition
      - Supplemental file
        - Centenary of Freud's birth, exhibit material, circa 1956
          - Photographs
            - Prints
              - Bernays and Freud families (Container 136)
              - People identified and unidentified (Container 136)
              - Portraits of Freud
                - Paintings, drawings, cartoons, busts, statues, and medals (Container 136)
                - Photographs (Container 136)
              - Residences and other places associated with Freud (Container 136)
              - Writings and documents by or about Freud (Container 136)
          - Wall text and captions (2 folders) (Containers 136)
  - Empty display cases for pocket notebooks, undated (Container 50a) (Box OV 20)